Leonardo F. Guzman Papers VHP2005/10
CCSU Veterans History Project
Leonardo Feliciano Guzman Papers
Bulk, 1968-1970
1968 – 1970, 1975, 1976, 1980, 1988, 2004, 2005
VHP2005/10
CCSU Veterans History Project
300.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
This collection details Leonardo Guzman’s military training and experiences as an infantryman during his enlistment in the Vietnam War. The collection contains oral history interview, reproductions of scanned personal and military manuscripts, and photographs. The bulk of the materials, which date from 1968 thru 1970, provide evidence of Marine troop training, platoon deployment and assignments, enemy engagements (ambush sites, listening and observation posts, and firefights), civilian protests, and the affects of antiwar sentiments on Vietnam veterans.
Guzman, Leonardo F., (Leonardo Feliciano), 1947 -
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
Biographical/Historical note
Leonardo Guzman enlisted in the United States Marine Corps in 1968. The Caguas, Puerto Rico native received basic training at Parris Island in South Carolina, advanced infantry training at Camp Lejeune in North Carolina, and additional training and preparation for his assignment in Vietnam on the island of Okinawa. After landing at Ton Son Nhut Air Base in 1968 Leonardo served in An Hoa (outside Da Nang) as a member of the 1st Division, 5th Regiment3rd Battalion. While in Vietnam his battalion also operated out of the Arizona Territory, Que Son, Hiep Duc, Song Chug, and Go Noi Island. For his valiant service Lance Corporal Guzman received the Presidential Unit Citation, the Vietnam Campaign Medal, the Vietnam Service Medal, the Vietnam Cross of Gallantry, and the Combat Action Ribbon.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Technical metadata of digital objects are extracted and encoded in PREMIS preservation metadata format
Preservation Metadata
Arrangement note
Series I: Presonal Papers
Series II: Publications
Series III: Multi-Media
United States. Marine Corps. Regiment, 5th. Battalion, 3rd. Company K .; United States. Marine Corps.; An Hoa (Vietnam); Camp Lejeune (N.C.); Hawaii; Ho Chi Minh Trail; Interviews; Malaria; Manuscript; Okinawa-shi (Japan); Parris Island (S.C.); Photographs; Thailand; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Personal narrative, American
- Series I: Personal Papers, VHP2005/10.I
  - 1st Marine division plaque presented by Major General Ormond R. Simpson, USMC., 1969; VHP2005/10.I.1
  - Certificates of service, 1970; VHP2005/10.I.2
  - Military decorations, n.d.; VHP2005/10.I.3
  - Letter of appreciation acknowledging Leonardo Guzman’s service during the Vietnam War., May 20, 1970; VHP2005/10.I.4
  - DD Form 214, Discharge Papers and Separation Documents, 1970; VHP2005/10.I.5
  - DD from 215, Addendum to discharge form DD214, Oct. 28, 1988; VHP2005/10.I.6
  - Interview synopsis, Dec. 14, 2005; VHP2005/10.I.7
- Series II: Publications, VHP2005/10.II
  - Marine Corps Recruit Depot Publication, 1968; VHP2005/10.II.1; 97.0 Digital objects
    General note
    Published by Albert Love Enterprises, Inc. in Doraville, Georgia, this pictorial booklet provides information on the Marine recruitment depot located at Parris Island, South Carolina. The booklet contain messages from General Leonard F. Chapman, Jr., U.S. Marine Corps Commandant, Colonel James G. Juett, Commanding Officer, and Major General Ormond R. Simpson, Commanding General. It provides brief textual information about the mission, history, and training at the recruitment depot, while candid photographs depict various operations, trainings, and military standards.
  - First Marine Division Volume III - Vietnam, 2004; VHP2005/10.II.2; 112.0 Digital objects
    Illustrated booklet published by the Turner Publishing Company Nashville, Tennessee in 2004. This booklet describes the history of the First Division in Vietnam, including special stories and division biographies. Leonardo Guzman’s biography can be found on page 98
- Series III: Multi-Media, VHP2005/10.III
  - Subseries A: Still Images, VHP2005/10.III
    - Leonardo Guzman Guzman posing in front of unknown building, 1966; VHP2005/10.III.1
    - Boot camp graduation photograph of Leonardo Guzman Guzman in dress uniform, 1968; VHP2005/10.III.2
    - Leonardo Guzman kneeling in front of unknown building during Advanced Infantry training with V2 Company., 1968; VHP2005/10.III.3
    - Leonardo Guzman kneeling in front of unknown building, 1968; VHP2005/10.III.4
    - Leonardo Guzman wearing fatigues and a black beret in base camp standing in front of a wooden tower, 1968; VHP2005/10.III.5
    - Leonardo Guzman wearing fatigues standing next to a tent, 1968; VHP2005/10.III.6
    - Leonardo Guzman Guzman and squad leader Clark preparing for mission, 1968; VHP2005/10.III.7
    - Squad leader Clark posing in front of unknown building, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.8
    - Squad leader Clark and sonny (grenade launcher) sitting on wooden palettes, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.9
    - Corpsman John Schnovel and unknown Marine at base camp, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.10
    - Corpsman John Schnovel in base camp with a group of Marines, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.11
    - United States Marine entering "Alabama" (the supply tent), Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.12
    - Cooking Spam, Leonardo Guzman Guzman (rear left), Moe (rear right), Sergeant Morales (front left) and an unknown Marine (front right)., 1968; VHP2005/10.III.13
    - 60 millimeter mortars with rocket launcher, 1968; VHP2005/10.III.14
    - Leonardo Guzman Guzman posing in front of a "hideaway" tent, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.15
    - Corpsman John Schnovel with a towel over his shoulder, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.16
    - Writing Home: Left to right, a Vietnamese Scout, Leonardo Guzman Guzman and Corpsman John Schnovel, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.17
    - Leonardo Guzman sitting on bunk in hootch, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.18
    - Marines preparing for a mission, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.19
    - Raymond preparing for a mission, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.20
    - Squad leader standing in front of a bunker, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.21
    - Chinook helicopter landing, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.22
    - View of combat base with helicopter landing in the background, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.23
    - Unknown Marines protecting the road from Da Nang to An Hoa, Vietnam, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.24
    - Leonardo Guzman talking on a field phone on the road from Da Nang to An Hoa, Vietnam, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.25
    - Leonardo Guzman sitting among the grass on the road from Da Nang to An Hoa, Vietnam, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.26
    - Leonardo Guzman kneeling in a field in "Arizona territory", Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.27
    - Two Marines posing for camera. Left to right Jack and unidentified Marine in Arizona territory, Vietnam, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.28
    - Three Marines in the bush. Left to right, Leonardo Guzman, unknown Marine and Perdue in Arizona territory, Vietnam., Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.29
    - Leonardo Guzman (left) and Corpsman John Schnovel, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.30
    - Leonardo Guzman drinking a beverage in a dug out hole while on a mission, 1968; VHP2005/10.III.31
    - Corpsman John Schnovel eating rations on a mission, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.32
    - Jacko wearing jacket and hat while on a mission during the rainy season, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.33
    - Three Marines posing for a photograph. Left to right, Jacko, Brian and an unidentified soldier at "Liberty Bridge," Vietnam., Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.34
    - Two Marines posing for a photograph while on a mission, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.35
    - Leonardo Guzman lying on a bunk relaxing in front of "Charlie Ridge" mountains, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.36
    - Leonardo Guzman and Smitty, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.37
    - Leonardo Guzman (left) in a hat posing with Corpsman John Schnovel at "Liberty Bridge, Vietnam, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.38
    - Leonardo Guzman digging a foxhole at "Hobo Woods," Vietnam, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.39
    - Leonardo Guzman (back) and Corpsman John Schnovel roughhousing in a foxhole at "Hobo Woods," Vietnam, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.40
    - "Hole digger" Corpsman John Schnovel sitting on the side of a foxhole at "Hobo Woods," Vietnam., Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.41
    - Corpsman John Schnovel digging a foxhole at "Hobo Woods," Vietnam, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.42
    - Vietnamese village with women and children, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.43
    - Leonardo Guzman during a mission to Go Noi Island, Vietnam, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.44
    - Leonardo Guzman standing between two Thai soldiers while on R & R leave (Rest & Relaxation). Bangkok, Thailand, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.45
    - Leonardo Guzman standing in front of a restaurant while on R&R leave. Bangkok, Thailand, Circa 1968; VHP2005/10.III.46
    - Waitress posing in front of restaurant. Bangkok, Thailand, Circa 1968; VHP2005/10.III.47
    - United States cemetery at Bastogne, Belgium, 1975; VHP2005/10.III.48
      Graves of military personnel killed during the Battle of Bastogne.
    - United States cemetery at Bastogne, Belgium, 1975; VHP2005/10.III.49
    - United States cemetery at Bastogne, 1975; VHP2005/10.III.50
    - Gunnery Sergeant Gayle. Camp Lejeune (N.C.), 1976; VHP2005/10.III.51
    - Gunnery Sergeant Gayle standing in front of brick building. Camp Lejeune (N.C.), 1976; VHP2005/10.III.52
    - Leonardo Guzman sitting in front of brick building. Camp Lejeune (N.C.), 1976; VHP2005/10.III.53
    - Michael Williams and Leonardo Guzman under a tarp at bivouac area. Camp Lejeune (N.C.), 1976; VHP2005/10.III.54
    - Leonardo Guzman posing in civilian clothing while on a weekend pass. Fort Dix (N.J.), 1976; VHP2005/10.III.55
    - Leonardo Guzman standing beside locker. Camp Lejeune (N.C.), 1976; VHP2005/10.III.56
    - Leonardo Guzman and his uncle John Guzman. Littleton (N.H.), 1980; VHP2005/10.III.57
    - Leonardo Guzman seated at Central Connecticut State University, 2005; VHP2005/10.III.58
    - Marine infantry training platoon posing in helmets, Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.59
    - U.S. Marine Platoon 3002 posed on bleachers in front of platoon flag and rifles., Between 1968 and 1970; VHP2005/10.III.60
  - Subseries B: Moving Images, VHP2005/10.IIIb
    - Oral history interview, Dec 4, 2005; VHP2005/10.IIb.1; 1.0 dvd; Hurst, Eileen (Disk DVD VHP2005/10, Box VHP Interviews #1)